Schuyler Williams

schuylerwilliams.github.io

2184 Babcock Lane, Delavan WI 53115 (262) 374-1086 — skywilliams@gmail.com

Profile

A geographic expert with 3+ years experience in supervisory/management roles and GIS/computer programming development. Specializing in efficient communication solutions, web and application design and development, team coordination, and human geographic analysis. Now seeking to contribute my learned skills and experiences to the defense and prosperity of the United States of America.

Experience

GIS Lab Manager — Department of Forest and Wildlife

-Madison, WI - 2016-Current

- Communicating and resolving issues
- Oversight and training of all new hires
- Quality control of all work being completed
- Delegate and coordinate responsibilities
- · Run monthly meetings
- Maintain lab website and develop mapping applications

GIS Ecological Technician — Department of Forest and Wildlife

-Madison, WI - 2015-2016

- Digitize and attribute land cover maps
- Responsible for updating progress map
- Create point and line features on georeferenced map image
- Work as a team to achieve efficiency and deadline goals

Waiter — The Grandview

—Lake Geneva, WI - 2015

- Responsible for serving and accommodating customer
- Worked as a team and self-managed on the patio dining
- Handled issues or concerns of the guest
- Multitasking and time-management in high demand situations

Student Supervisor — UW-Madison Union

- Hired as custodial, promoted to supervisor within 3 weeks
- Responsible for shift reports and custodial workers
- Resolve issues that arise with custodial workers
- Light cleanup of offices and building where needed

-Madison, WI - 2014-2015

Bus Person — The Grandview

-Lake Geneva, WI - 2010-2014

- Keeping customers happy and satisfied
- Aided coworkers responsibilities in high-demand times
- Organizing and maintaining appearance of restaurant
- Communicated to managers the needs of the customer, as well as finding solutions to those needs

Education

University of Wisconsin, Madison — Pursuing Degree

- Enrolled as a Senior, expected graduation date May 2017 with dual degree in Cartography / GIS and Geography
- deans list?
- Coursework involved GIS spatial analysis, web development, computer programming, human geographic analysis, remote sensing analysis, and research topics

Skills

Programming

• SQL, PHP, Python, HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Javascript

GIS Software

• GDAL, OGR, Leaflet, Openlayers, Mapbox, Esri ArcGIS products, QGIS, Envi, Google Earth

Computer Programs & Software

 Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Acrobat, GIMP, Inkscape, MS Office, AutoDesk Maya, AutoCAD, Microsoft OS, Mac OS, Linux, SketchUp, Blender, Unreal Engine, Unity